should you title
Calis that's a good question um it
depends what you're using it for so I
I've I've written a couple of times
about my thoughts on sealas I think that
ultimately the goal you know especially
for a younger man if a man's in his you
know late 60s or 70s and so forth you
know different story but if we're
talking about a young guy here if if a
young guy is using sealas for erectile
dysfunction we ultimately want to
resolve the need for that so I think the
long-term goal should be not to require
CLS for sexual function however what we
all know is that the sexual benefits of
trt take time to kick in um six months
12 months potentially longer if a guy's
health is particularly derailed it might
take him you know 12 to 24 months to
resolve things like insulin resistance
excess body fat um you know improving
his cardiovascular health improving his
mental confidence all of those kind of
things having a good sexual relationship
with his partner all of those things
take time so seis can be a good thing
that can work as a Band-Aid in the
interim especially if the lack of sexual
function is burdening or stressing the
relationship if someone's married or
living with a partner and their
inability to maintain an erection is
causing strain in the relationship I
think daily Calis for the first X months
of of treatment typically three to six
months is a fantastic way to Fast Track
those benefits to be able to have those
more holistic benefits around intimacy
um and what I find a lot of the time is
that once guys get to the 3 to six month
Mark they just forget to take it they
just go oh I don't need this anymore and
then it just it just works out of their
system the only dependence risk of Calis
is a psychological dependence that
people think that they can't perform
without it um it doesn't cause a
physiological dependence but most people
will attest in practice that if I think
it's kind of like caffeine if you don't
drink coffee ever and then you have a
coffee it's going to hit you a lot
harder than it would if you were taking
it daily but it still has the effect
that it that it should be producing
daily so if people want to get the most
bang for their Buck out of seis for like
you know a one night performance then
yeah taking it without using it
regularly does in practice yield a
stronger effect but it doesn't mean that
using it daily is subject to some kind
of massive tolerance or it stops working
so I don't think it needs to be cycled
and I think if CLS is need needed for
erection function the dose can be put up
5 milligrams of Calis is not very much
um Calis is well studied in 20 or even
40 milligram doses a day so if guys do
have legitimate erectile dysfunction
while they're waiting for their
testosterone dose to G in and the five
milligrams of sealas isn't cutting the
mustard 10 milligrams of Calis a day is
a very reasonable dose to use and
additional things can be used in in
conjunction like things like citrine I
think guys should be focusing on you
know cardiovascular health reducing
stress stuff like that but the dose can
be escalated of it while it's needed but
yeah so I don't think it needs to be
cycled I think it more needs to be
looked at as a I'm using this for a
period until I no longer need it